- [Ray] There's two reasons why,
if I had to learn only one JavaScript framework,
it would be React.
Now first, the speed at which
it's dominated the industry is amazing.
If I was looking for a job today
as a front end or full stack developer,
chances are it's on the list of preferred skills.
But the second reason is more important.
It's a lot of fun to code in.
React makes things that are annoying,
like managing the virtual DOM, trivial.
Hey there, this is Ray Villalobos,
senior staff instructor at LinkedIn,
and I created this course as a quick introduction to React
that will teach you how it works in a practical way.
I'm using React Hooks in this course,
the most modern way of working with the library.
I'm assuming you know the basics of HTML,
CSS, and JavaScript, and that's about it.
Now, we're going to build a simple application
that will get you some experience with React
and show you why it's worth your time.
So if you're ready to build an interactive project,
let's get started.