- [Instructor] The create-react-app
makes it easier to create a project
by installing a lot of modules.
So let's go over what we got when we installed the project
with create react app.
I'm going to go over to the desktop
and look at the folder that was installed
and I'm going to drag it onto my code editor
which is Visual Studio Code.
Now a couple of notes.
If you're comfortable with react installations,
you might want to skip this video.
Also, if you're working with our GitHub repo, like I am,
you'll see some additional files and folders
like the contributing license, notice, GitHub folder,
and a different read me file than the default installation.
Those are required for us to add the projects on GitHub
but the rest is the default installation.
Now let's go ahead and run the npm start
or the yarn start command.
So I'm going to pull up a terminal
and go to the terminal menu and select new terminal
and then type in the npm start or yarn start command.
If it does give you this message just go ahead and say, yes.
This will startup our application in a browser.
Let's talk about some of the modules
that get installed when you use create react app.
First Webpack is a JavaScript bundler.
Its main job is to manage how our application is assembled
and the loading of your different modules
into an application.
Babel is a JavaScript compiler,
it lets you write code with the latest JavaScript features
and it will convert that,
so that it works with older browsers.
Est Lint is a JavaScript linter
which analyzes your code against certain rules
and helps you fix them.
You might need to have an extension installed
on your editor to use this,
and you can find one for Visuals Studio Code
at the links right here.
You also get Jest, a testing framework.
And if you want to run tests on your JavaScript code,
you can use that.
Finally, you'll also get something called Web Vitals
which is a performance monitoring tool for your site
measuring performance, accessibility, and best practices.
Now you can see the modules that I was talking about
installed right here.
So for example you can see jest install right there,
as well as the testing version
for the react library of jest
and some of the other tools that we talked about
into the package.json file.
Now the package.json is the file that Node.js creates
to manage my project.
You can also see a browser list section down here.
This helps our modules like Webpack
note which browsers you're targeting for the build.
You can see that we're targeting browsers
that are not opera mini.
The getignore file is a document that helps you control
which files are tracked by GitHub.
So for example, the node modules folder
is not going to be copied to your GitHub repo.
Now let's see how this project is put together.
The files are in two main folders.
The public folder has files that Webpack will manage.
They will also be moved to the server
when our project is deployed.
You can see that there are some icons as well as logos here
that show up when we preview our application.
The robots.txt file gives web crawlers
information about your sites.
Web crawlers are applications that search engines
like Google use to get more information about your websites.
The index.html file is the entry point for browsers.
You can modify this file if you want,
but Webpack will use this file
to inject the JavaScript code you write
as well as react code and other CSS.
The single most important section
is this div with the id of root.
This is where your application will be loaded.
Now let's look at some of the react files.
The other main folder is this source folder.
And here you'll find the index.js file.
This is your entry point for the JavaScript application.
Now this file is going to import a lot of code
from different libraries like React and React-dom.
React is the main library for working with react
while React-dom manages
how the document object model works within react.
Now these are being loaded by Node.js
using what's listed as dependencies
in your package.json file.
If you're looking for where these files are coming from,
they're coming from the node_modules folder.
Since we're using Webpack,
you can include your CSS as an import
with a command like import right here.
Now that's instead of using a link tag in your HTML
this is going to let you have a CSS file
for your entire application.
We're also importing a configuration file
for web report vitals
and this is the module that we talked about earlier.
Now we're calling that function right here at the bottom.
Another import we're doing is for a react module called App.
Although you don't see the extension,
this is loading the file called app.js.
You getignore extensions
when you load other JavaScript files.
Now we're using the react library inside our render command.
You can see some code to put react in StrictMode
during development.
StrictMode will complain
if you write potentially dangerous code.
The render command
then loads up the app component as a module
and looks for an item with the Id of root in your index
that html file
and that's where your application will be loaded.
Now let's take a look at App.js next.
There's a load command here for a file called logo.svg,
which is in the same folder you can see it right here.
You can include images and logos in here
but they will be managed by Webpack
which can be useful in automating things like compression
but it means that they won't be in the final folder
that is exposed to the web.
We're also loading a test for this document
that's in a file called App.test.js.
We installed the jest testing library
and this code shows some sample test code.
This are related file called setupTests.js down here.
In the same way, we're loading an App.css file right here.
Then we have a function that defines our document.
I should mention that,
although the code follows what looks to be JavaScript,
it's written in a language called JSX
which is a combination of JavaScript and HTML.
So you can see that we use a return statement right here
inside the function called App
and then we export default
just like we would for a normal JavaScript project.
So that part looks like JavaScript.
And then all the code right here looks like regular HTML
but do notice that there are some changes.
So for example, we can import a variable right here
which is this logo that we imported earlier.
And whenever we use the keyword class in HTML,
we have to modify that to className
because class means something in JavaScript.
We can't use that in JSX.
So we have to always remember to use className
instead of class
and there are a lot of other places
where you're going to have to remember
to use the JSX version of the HTML.
Also notice that standalone tags
like the image tag,
have to have this closing slash right here.
So that's how our application loads.
Now there's a lot going on here
but hopefully everything makes sense.